Rustam Khuseinov

Frontend Software Engineer

I am a software engineer specializing in frontend development. My passion is creating web applications that combine functionality and visual inspiration. Outside of work, my interests extend to the world of video games, which inspires my creativity, and football, where I find a source of team spirit and passion. My goal is to apply my skills and passions to create unique and outstanding web applications.

Experience

Oct 2021 – Present Dushanbe, Tajikistan

Frontend developer at Profisites (Remote) ∅

- Conducted a successful project migration process from using vanilla HTML, CSS and JavaScript to more modern technologies, including TypeScript, React and Styled Components.
- Using the i18n library, I translated part of the application interface into English.
- Introduced updated technologies and design solutions for websites, which simplified development and reduced the time spent on selecting products and placing orders by more than 50%.

Jun 2021 – Oct 2021 Kazan, Russia

Internship at Aston 🔗

- Participation in the Online JS Core intensive, which included theoretical classes, practice and homework, which gave me a solid foundation in JavaScript, HTML/CSS and working with Git.
- Continuation of the internship as part of the Online React-intensive, with an
 emphasis on developing web applications in React and TypeScript, as well as
 participation in group projects.
- Completion of an internship at the Laboratory, where, under the guidance of experienced specialists, I developed not only technical skills, but also soft skills, preparing for work on commercial projects.

Oct 2020 – Jun 2021 Kazan, Russia

Self-education

rustamkhuseinov.com @

• In-depth study of JavaScript/TypeScript/React and related technologies using them in your own projects.

Technical Skill

Front End Development

TypeScript, JavaScript(ES6+), React, Redux (Thunk,Toolkit), HTML, CSS, SCSS/Sass, Webpack, Vite, Parcel, Styled Components, Framer Motion

Tools & Platforms

Git, GitHub, Figma, Photoshop, Postman, Jest, Jira, Vercel, Netlify, Trello.

Education

2018 – 2023 Kazan National Research Technological University
 Bachelor's Degree in Tourism
 2016 – 2018 Kazan State University
 Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science